<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Olivia Zhang</title><link>https://via-zhang.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Olivia Zhang</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://via-zhang.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Geospatial Data Workshop at the Student Sustainability Summit</title><link>https://via-zhang.github.io/posts/s3-summit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://via-zhang.github.io/posts/s3-summit/</guid><description>&lt;p>Combining my passions for climate action, data science, and geography, I had the incredible opportunity to present at the 2025 &lt;a href="https://www.studentsustainabilitysummit.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Student Sustainability Summit&lt;/a>. Along with two other University of Florida students, I led a workshop introducing how to analyze spatial data about wildfires in California as part of our presentation about the intersection of data science and sustainability.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="data-science-for-sustainable-development">Data Science for Sustainable Development&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In August 2024, I co-founded &lt;a href="https://gainesville.dssdglobal.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Data Science for Sustainable Development (DSSD)&lt;/a> at the University of Florida as a chapter of the &lt;a href="https://dssdglobal.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">nonprofit DSSD&lt;/a>. DSSD’s mission is to apply &lt;b>technology for positive impact&lt;/b> in support of the Sustainable Development Goals. We provide technical services to nonprofits, startups, and researchers for web development, data analysis, and other projects&amp;mdash;all led by innovative teams of students passionate about data, computer science, and sustainability. At the Student Sustainability Summit, we presented about our ongoing projects and led an interactive coding workshop about analyzing fires in California.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vibrance of Miami, a Data Storytelling Project</title><link>https://via-zhang.github.io/posts/miami-vibrance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://via-zhang.github.io/posts/miami-vibrance/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;code>Vibrance of Miami&lt;/code> takes a look at the diversity and resilience of Miami from space, using publicly-available data. Miami has grown so much over the years, and we can visualize this through how the lights of Miami, captured by satellites at night, have become brighter. Miami has so much diversity and color everywhere you look, and I hope that this artwork can reflect that vibrant joy.
&lt;img src="Vibrance_of_Miami.gif" alt="A digital self portrait, overlaid with a series of white lines and a timelapse of nighttime lights over Miami.">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Detecting Shell Mounds in LiDAR Images</title><link>https://via-zhang.github.io/posts/shell-mounds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://via-zhang.github.io/posts/shell-mounds/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="project-overview">Project Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Shell mounds, or shell middens, are hills of accumulated shell (clams, oysters, and whelks), mud bricks, pottery shards, and other objects built up by generations of Indigenous peoples (Orengo et al., 2020; Florida Natural Areas Inventory, 2010). Shell mounds, found along the coastlines of the southeastern United States (Florida Natural Areas Inventory, 2010), give us a look at the past, helping us understand the lives of communities from hundreds to thousands of years ago. As such, they are a crucial part of our cultural landscape—imprinted evidence of history and heritage on the natural landscape (Taylor &amp;amp; Lennon, 2011).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Community Engagement &amp; Civic Technology</title><link>https://via-zhang.github.io/posts/bcls-fellow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://via-zhang.github.io/posts/bcls-fellow/</guid><description>&lt;p>In my first year at the University of Florida (UF), I participated in the Path to Purpose Fellowship with UF&amp;rsquo;s Brown Center for Leadership &amp;amp; Service. The fellowship is centered on local, impactful, collaborative action for social change. Throughout the year, I learned about conscious community engagement, ensuring that we co-create solutions with the community here in Gainesville, Florida. We embraced opportunities to be involved with vibrant and inspiring social change initiatives.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>