<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data on Olivia Zhang</title>
    <link>https://via-zhang.github.io/tags/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data on Olivia Zhang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://via-zhang.github.io/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Geospatial Data Workshop at the Student Sustainability Summit</title>
      <link>https://via-zhang.github.io/posts/s3-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://via-zhang.github.io/posts/s3-summit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Combining my passions for climate action, data science, and geography, I had the incredible opportunity to present at the 2025 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.studentsustainabilitysummit.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Student Sustainability Summit&lt;/a&gt;. Along with two other University of Florida students, I led a workshop introducing how to analyze spatial data about wildfires in California as part of our presentation about the intersection of data science and sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-science-for-sustainable-development&#34;&gt;Data Science for Sustainable Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In August 2024, I co-founded &lt;a href=&#34;https://gainesville.dssdglobal.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Data Science for Sustainable Development (DSSD)&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Florida as a chapter of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dssdglobal.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;nonprofit DSSD&lt;/a&gt;. DSSD’s mission is to apply &lt;b&gt;technology for positive impact&lt;/b&gt; in support of the Sustainable Development Goals. We provide technical services to nonprofits, startups, and researchers for web development, data analysis, and other projects&amp;mdash;all led by innovative teams of students passionate about data, computer science, and sustainability. At the Student Sustainability Summit, we presented about our ongoing projects and led an interactive coding workshop about analyzing fires in California.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
